Register of the Alfred Max Loewenthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1886-1980 (Boxes 30-46)
  - Education, 1919-1979
    - General, 1919-1979 (Box-folder 32: 2-4)
    - Asia, 1967-1979 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - Central High School (Newark, New Jersey), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 33: 2)
      School newspaper and list of students, including Loewenthal.
    - Newark Students League (independent organization), circa 1930s (Box-folder 33: 3)
      New Student.
    - Taiwan, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Europe, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Germany, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    Includes reports on Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung.
  - Great Britain, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1977 (Box-folder 33: 8)
    Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs opening program.
  - International relations, 1948-1979
    - General, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
    - Foreign Report (Economist Newspaper Limited), 1975-1979 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - International Sakharov Hearings, Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    Transcripts of testimony.
  - Ireland, 1886-1966 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    Includes W. E. Gladstone, The Irish Question, and Brendan Mary MacThormaid, Deathless Glory.
  - Israel and the Middle East, 1954-1980
    - General, 1954-1979 (Box-folder 35: 2-3)
      Includes press releases of the Israeli Embassy in the United States and other Israeli publications.
    - Israel Digest, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 35: 4)
    - Near East Report, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Jews, 1943-1979 (Box-folder 36: 2-3)
    Mainly publications of various American Jewish organizations.
  - Jordan, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Labor (international), 1951-1980
    - General, 1952-1979 (Box-folder 36: 5)
    - AFL-CIO Department of International Affairs, 1968-1980
      - General, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 36: 6)
        Includes articles about the AFL-CIO role in international affairs.
      - AFL-CIO Free Trade Union News, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 36: 7)
    - Africa, 1955-1979 (Box-folder 37: 1)
      Includes pamphlets and reports about labor in Sierra Leone, South Africa, Tunisia, and Uganda.
    - African-American Labor Center issuances, 1977-1979
      - General, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 37: 2)
        Includes AALC Reporter issues; Colloquium on African Trade Union Research Services; J. Dennis Akumu, The Role of Trade Unionism in Development; David Klugman, Trade Unions, Cooperatives, Credit Unions in Africa; and George R. Martens, Trade Unions and Nation Building in Francophone Africa.
      - African Trade Union News, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 37: 3)
      - Labor and Development, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 37: 4-5)
    - American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 6)
      Includes AIFLD Report issues.
    - Asian-American Free Labor Institute, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 7)
      AAFLI News issues.
    - Great Britain, 1946-1978 (Box-folder 37: 8)
      Includes Labour and Trades Union Press Service issues.
    - Hungary, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 38: 1)
      Hungarian Trade Union News issues.
    - International Labour Organisation issuances, 1952-1978 (Box-folder 38: 2)
    - Israel, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 38: 3)
      Includes Histadrut and American Histadrut Cultural Exchange Institute publications.
    - Japan, 1978 (Box-folder 38: 4)
      Untitled report.
    - Latin America, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 38: 5)
      Includes Organización Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores issuances, and reports on Argentina, Chile, Guyana, and Uruguay.
    - Soviet Union, 1951-1977 (Box-folder 38: 6)
      Mainly Soviet pamphlets.
    - Soviet Union (cont'd.), 1951-1977 (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
    - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1975-1979
      - General, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 39: 3)
        Mainly World Federation of Trade Union declarations.
      - Flashes from the Trade Unions, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 39: 4)
      - World Trade Union Movement, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Labor--United States, 1955-1980
    - General, 1955-1979 (Box-folder 39: 6)
    - General (cont'd.), 1955-1979 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
    - AFL-CIO issuances, 1957-1980
      - Constitutions, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 40: 3)
      - Convention proceedings, 1957-1979
        - 2nd convention, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1957 (Box-folder 40: 4)
        - 7th convention, Bal Harbour, Florida, 1967 (Box-folder 40: 5)
        - 9th constitutional convention, Bal Harbour, Florida, 1971 (Box-folder 41: 1)
        - 13th convention, Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box-folder 41: 2-3)
      - Publications, 1963-1980
        - AFL-CIO American Federationist, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 41: 4)
        - Viewpoint, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 42: 1)
        - Miscellaneous, 1963-1980 (Box-folder 42: 2)
      - Publications of individual unions, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 42: 3)
      - Resolutions and platform proposals, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - AFL-CIO Department for Professional Employees issuances, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 42: 5)
      Includes Martin H. Dodd, Professional Workers and Unionization: A Survey, policy statements, and minutes.
    - AFL-CIO Department for Professional Employees issuances (cont'd.), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - Jewish Labor Committee and Workmen's Circle issuances, 1958-1979 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees issuances, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 43: 3)
    - New Jersey State CIO Council officers' reports, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 43: 4)
    - Seminar on Maintaining Non-Union Status, 1974 (Box-folder 43: 5-6)
      Transcript of a management anti-union presentation by Charles Hughes and Scott Myers.
    - Textile Workers Union issuances, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Workers Defense League anniversary publication, circa 1971 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Latin America, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 44: 3)
  - Law, 1948-1955 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - League for Industrial Democracy issuances, 1952-1978 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - Liberal Party of New York State, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    Programs and anniversary publication.
  - Nuclear warfare, 1945-1979 (Box-folder 44: 7)
    Includes leaflets and petitions by SANE and the New Jersey Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, in which Loewenthal was active.
  - Socialism, 1949-1979 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - Soviet Union, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 44: 9)
    Includes Peter Reddaway, "Socialist Legality, Soviet Psychiatry, and the Campaign against Their Corrupt Interaction."
  - Technology, 1979 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Trotskyism, 1941-1977 (Box-folder 45: 2)
    Includes press coverage of prosecution of American Trotskyists during World War II.
  - United States--Politics, 1948-1979 (Box-folder 45: 3-5)
    Includes labor political action committee pamphlets and leaflets, and articles re Proposition 13 in California.
  - Miscellany, 1906-1980 (Box-folder 46: 1)
- LEFT-WING PUBLICATIONS, 1903-1980 (Boxes 46-58)
  Pamphlets, serial issues, and internal publications of left-wing political groups.
  - Anarchist and associated publications, 1927-1974
    - Politics, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - Resistance, 1953 (Box-folder 46: 4)
    - Pamphlets, 1927-1974 (Box-folder 46: 5)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A., and associated publications, 1924-1978
    - Communist, 1933 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - International Press Correspondence, 1928-1934 (Box-folder 47: 2)
    - New World Review, 1971 (Box-folder 47: 3)
    - Red International of Labour Unions, 1928 (Box-folder 47: 4)
    - World Marxist Review, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box-folder 47: 5-6)
    - Pamphlets by V. I. Lenin, 1924-1940 (Box-folder 48: 1-3)
    - Pamphlets by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels, 1933-1972 (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - Pamphlets by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels (cont'd.), 1933-1972 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Pamphlets by Georgi Plekhanov, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 2)
    - Pamphlets by others, 1926-1977 (Box-folder 49: 3-4)
  - Socialist and associated publications, 1903-1980
    - British socialist publications, 1917-1955
      - Plebs, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 49: 5)
      - Socialist Commentary, 1955 (Box-folder 49: 6)
      - Pamphlets, 1917-1938 (Box-folder 49: 7)
    - Charles H. Kerr and Company pamphlets, 1905-1975 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee issuances, circa 1973 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - Guardian, 1979 (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - International Review pamphlets, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 50: 4)
    - International Socialist Review, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 50: 5-6)
    - Modern Monthly, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 50: 7)
    - Modern Review, 1947 (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - New International Review, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 51: 2)
    - New Politics, 1961-1964
      - 1961 (Box-folder 51: 3)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 51: 4-5)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 51: 6)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - Rand School of Social Science pamphlets and bulletin, 1917-1955 (Box-folder 52: 2)
    - Social Democrats, U.S.A., publications, 1975-1980
      - New America, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 52: 3)
      - SD Quarterly, 1979 (Box-folder 52: 4)
      - Socialist Currents, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 5)
      - Pamphlets, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 52: 6)
    - Socialist Labor Party and Industrial Union Party pamphlets and journal article, 1903-1978 (Box-folder 52: 7-8)
    - Socialist Party and associated publications, 1919-1971
      - New America, 1971 (Box-folder 52: 9)
      - New Leader, 1955 (Box-folder 52: 10)
      - Pamphlets, leaflets and article, 1919-1956 (Box-folder 52: 11)
    - Western Socialist (World Socialist Party), 1948 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - Workers Age Publishers pamphlets, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets and articles, 1918-1978 (Box-folder 53: 3-4)
  - Trotskyist and associated publications, 1926-1978
    - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky pamphlets and other issuances, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 53: 5)
    - Civil Rights Defense Committee bulletins re trial of Trotskyists, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 53: 6)
    - Leninist League/Workers League for a Revolutionary Party publications, 1940-1948
      - Bulletin, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 54: 1)
      - Pamphlets, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 54: 2)
    - Socialist Workers Party publications, 1929-1978
      - Internal bulletins, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 54: 3)
      - Educational bulletins, 1938-1946 (Box-folder 54: 4-5)
      - Fourth International, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 55: 1)
      - New International, 1934-1940 (Box-folder 55: 2-4)
      - Pamphlets by Leon Trotsky, 1929-1975 (Box-folder 55: 5-6)
      - Pamphlets by Leon Trotsky (cont'd.), 1929-1975 (Box-folder 56: 1-2)
      - Pamphlets by others, 1933-1978 (Box-folder 56: 3-4)
      - Pamphlets by others (cont'd.), 1933-1978 (Box-folder 57: 1-2)
      - Flyers, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 57: 3)
    - Workers Party/Independent Socialist League publications, 1940-1958
      - Labor Action, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 57: 4)
      - New International, 1940 (Box-folder 57: 5)
      - Pamphlets, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 57: 6)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. Trotskyist issuances, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 57: 7)
    - Student publications, 1947-1960
      - Anvil and Student Partisan, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 58: 1)
      - Student Partisan, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 58: 2)
    - Articles and other publications by Leon Trotsky in the mainstream press, 1926-1938 (Box-folder 58: 3-4)
    - British Trotskyist publications, 1943-1947
      - Workers International News, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 58: 5)
      - Pamphlets, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 58: 6)
    - Other non-U.S. Trotskyist publications (India, South Africa, Sri Lanka), 1945-1951 (Box-folder 58: 7)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, undated (Box 59, Film shelf)
  Caricatures, photographs, printing mattes, and motion picture film.
  - Caricatures (Box-folder 59: 1)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 59: 2)
  - Photographic printing mattes (Box-folder 59: 3)
  - Motion picture film, 2.0 motion picture film reels (Film shelf)
    - "Kennedy Goldwater," 16mm film, undated
    - "9-25 PAT IOE-CIO," 16mm film, silent, undated
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1898-1974 (Boxes 60-64)
  Serial issues, articles, blueprints, and a cartoon.
  - Life issues, 1963-1970 (Box 60)
    Related to Africa, Christianity, Nikita Khrushchev, Winston Churchill, Jacqueline Kennedy, and Martin Luther King, Jr.
  - Ebony issues, 1968-1969
    Related to Martin Luther King, Jr. and black U.S. history.
  - Life and Look articles, circa 1955-1962 (Box 61)
    Related to art, history, labor, science, and the Russian Revolution.
  - New York Times Magazine issue, 1973
    Related to Israel.
  - This Week issue, 1968
    Related to Revolt in America.
  - Matchbox (Amnesty International) issue, 1974
    Related to human rights in the Soviet Union.
  - Soviet Life issues, 1971
    Related to the Communist Party of the Soviet Union.
  - USSR issue and article, 1968-1970
    Related to V. I. Lenin.
  - Original Gib Crockett (Washington Star) cartoon of James B. Carey, 1965 (Box 62)
  - Local 447 News (UE/IUE) issues, 1948-1959
  - IUE News bound volume, 1966
  - ILGWU Illustrated (International Ladies' Garment Workers Union convention publication), 1937
  - ILGWU News-History, 1900-1950 (International Ladies' Garment Workers Union convention publication)
  - Boston Herald Traveler special Labor Day issue, 1969
  - Young Spartacus bound volume, 1931-1934 (Box 63)
  - Militant issues, 1929
  - Organizer (Minnesota Trotskyist trade union journal) issues, 1934
  - Spanish Revolution issues, 1936-1937
  - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky News Bulletin issues, 1937
  - Revolutionary Age issues, 1937
  - Socialist Appeal issues, 1937
  - Spain and the World issues, 1937
  - Truth about the Moscow Trials issues, 1937
  - Militant (Great Britain) issues, 1938
  - New America commemorative issue re Norman Thomas, 1968
  - Militant commemorative issue re James P. Cannon, 1974
  - Harper's Weekly issue, 1898
  - Evening Post (New York) 100th anniversary issue, 1901
  - Carolina Israelite (Charlotte, North Carolina) issues, 1958-1961
  - Fairviewer (Verona, New Jersey, High School) issues, 1960-1961
  - Rutgers Daily Targum (Rutgers University) issues, 1961
  - Indonesia (Djakarta) issue, 1954
  - Beacon (Bridgetown, Barbados) issues, 1955
  - C.O.A.S.I. (Comite Obrero de Accion Sindical Independiente de Argentina) issues, 1955
  - Labour Advocate (Georgetown, British Guiana) issues, 1955
  - Torch (Valletta, Malta) issues, 1955
  - West African Worker (Accra, Ghana) issues, 1955
  - Original blueprints drawn by Loewenthal at the Newark College of Engineering, 1941 (Box 64)
  - Militant bound volume, 1933
  - Militant issues, 1933-1941
  - New Militant issues, 1934-1936
  - Socialist Appeal issues, 1938-1940
  - Industrial Organizer (Teamster Local 544, associated with Socialist Workers Party) issues, 1941